<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>_posts-rsses on Deniz Veli | The Modern Ink</title>
    <link>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in _posts-rsses on Deniz Veli | The Modern Ink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Deniz Veli 2016</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 05:15:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Etsy Local Goes Mobile</title>
      <link>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/etsy-local-goes-mobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 05:15:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/etsy-local-goes-mobile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://denizmveli.github.io/img/wp-uploads/2015/09/Etsy-Local_Blog.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Etsy Local&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week my anxiety and anticipation was building, as a whole lot of work from a great team of individuals I lead at Etsy was just about to be released to the world. And that feeling is exactly what I get out of bed and go to work for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then we launched the all new Etsy Local home screen tab on the Etsy app the iOS and Android!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Etsy Local you can find Etsy items and sellers near you, at events like pop-ups, craft fairs, and flea markets or local shops. Etsy sellers can add events like craft fairs and markets that they are selling at, and retailers that are part of Etsy Wholesale can have their brick-and-mortar stores included on Etsy Local as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on Etsy Local for most of this year, it&amp;rsquo;s with great excitement that I share the release of our new browsable Local experience in the Etsy app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;rsquo;s a great way to discover new sellers  and a great new channel for sellers to be found on Etsy, all while supporting the growth of local small businesses through commerce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read more about the launch from my colleague Johanna Beyenbach, over on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://etsy.me/1fT1oAe&#34;&gt;Etsy blog&lt;/a&gt;. You can find local stores and events happening in your neighborhood in the latest version of the Etsy shopping app, available on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.etsy.android&#34;&gt;Google Play Store&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/etsy/id477128284?mt=8&#34;&gt;Apple App Store&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android &amp; Design at Etsy</title>
      <link>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/android-design-at-etsy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2014 22:24:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/android-design-at-etsy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago my colleague &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/paulingford&#34;&gt;Paul Lau&lt;/a&gt; and I gave a talk at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/android-developers-nyc/events/169173012/&#34;&gt;NYC Android Meetup&lt;/a&gt;. We wanted to share our Android teams product development process at Etsy. How we collaborate as designers and developers to be effective at product development while experimenting and pushing our app UX as much as we can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our teams process is broken down into three parts each of which involve multiple iterations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ideas - Here we&amp;rsquo;re creating designs and soliciting feedback from as many stakeholders as possible. Each screen is designed for 5 inch phones plus 7 and 10 inch tablets. Designers explore variations of each screen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Implementation- Build it quick and iterate. Get your designers eyes on it as soon as possible. Developers make the UI code flexible as it will likely change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shipping- Freeze feature changes. Designers run through visual quality assurance (VQA). Iterate and make it great!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We included a few recent examples of screens we put together in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.etsy.android&#34;&gt;Etsy app&lt;/a&gt; and the some challenges we faced. Plus we added some implementation tips and tricks that help us stay flexible when building our UI layer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beautiful Android Design</title>
      <link>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/beautiful-android-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 07:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/beautiful-android-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://android-developers.blogspot.com.au/2013/12/beautiful-design-collection-winter-2013.html&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://denizmveli.github.io/img/wp-uploads/2013/12/Screen-Shot-2013-12-28-at-1.43.48-AM.png&#34; alt=&#34;Android Beautiful Design&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m super excited and very honored that Google recently placed our latest Etsy Android app on a very short list of the best Android apps released this season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read more over on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://android-developers.blogspot.com.au/2013/12/beautiful-design-collection-winter-2013.html&#34;&gt;Android Developers blog&lt;/a&gt; and if you haven&amp;rsquo;t yet been shopping on the new &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.etsy.android&#34;&gt;Etsy for Android&lt;/a&gt; app on your tablet or phone, this might be just the reminder you need.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Etsy Android Staggered Grid</title>
      <link>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/etsy-android-staggered-grid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 22:13:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/etsy-android-staggered-grid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week at Etsy we open sourced the staggered grid view from the new Etsy Android app. Somewhat surprisingly there&amp;rsquo;s been a large amount of interest from the Android community. I guess I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised. Whilst working on various apps I&amp;rsquo;ve found it challenging to implement advanced UI elements such as the staggered or masonry grid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://github-camo.global.ssl.fastly.net/a243ad5c2788730c40fc1d348e5ed85adb59c484/687474703a2f2f662e636c2e6c792f6974656d732f327a31423059304d3047304f326b316c334a30332f5472656e64696e672e706e67&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thankfully I had the opportunity during a recent project at Etsy to implement this grid view that would support advanced features such as rows of varying heights &amp;amp; syncing row positions across orientation changes. Before deciding to develop the grid, we did of course evaluate existing options available including the unfinished StaggeredGridView in the AOSP source. In the end we came to the conclusion that if we were going to build something stable, reliable and performant it was a necessity to understand the entire scope of how the grid functioned and to achieve that we decided to develop a new component.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m quite happy with the results. The grid was developed over the course of two weeks. During the project we tested the grid on a number of devices available in our awesome &lt;a href=&#34;http://codeascraft.com/2013/08/09/mobile-device-lab/&#34;&gt;Etsy Device Lab&lt;/a&gt;. We also found and fixed a couple of issues with the grid post launch using live crash logs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally after open sourcing the grid, we&amp;rsquo;ve promoted release artifacts for the initial version to Maven Central, and will maintain releases here ongoing. So now it&amp;rsquo;s a simple one-liner to add the AndroidStaggeredGrid to your project. Big thanks here go to Chris Banes for his helpful &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/chrisbanes/gradle-mvn-push&#34;&gt;Gradle plugin&lt;/a&gt; for uploading Android Artifacts to Maven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find out more, how the grid is used and also run the sample app over on the Etsy Github - &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/etsy/AndroidStaggeredGrid&#34;&gt;https://github.com/etsy/AndroidStaggeredGrid&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s all in the details</title>
      <link>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/its-all-in-the-details/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2013 14:56:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/its-all-in-the-details/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A great catalogue of the tiny design details that can make a big difference to a users experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All-New Etsy for Android App</title>
      <link>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/all-new-etsy-android-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2013 20:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/all-new-etsy-android-app/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am extremely excited and proud of the newly revamped and completely redesigned Etsy Android app which we rolled out to the public over the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After joining Etsy earlier this year our team set out on a project to bring the best of Android to the Etsy app. This included designing and building an app that was not only beautiful across multiple form factors, from phones to 7 &amp;amp; 10 inch tablets, but also included optimized screens for each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the way we tackled some interesting development challenges, like building a custom non-standard grid view to support our staggered list (see the trending list below), and developing multiple common components to accelerate our Android processes through reuse. We also added animations and visual effects like blur broadly across the app to create a richer more engaging app experience. Not to mention a totally new navigation system, a new activity feed, new browse categories, new shop info pages and a dual-pane tablet optimized conversations manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** Side note: if any of the above sounds interesting to you then you should know that we&amp;rsquo;re hiring - &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.etsy.com/careers/&#34;&gt;https://www.etsy.com/careers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.etsy.android&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://denizmveli.github.io/img/wp-uploads/2013/11/android-phone-trending-en.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Tablet View&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the whole project our goal for version 2 was to enable more Android users to connect to the amazing and diverse sellers that are making unique items on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.etsy.com&#34;&gt;Etsy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that you all enjoy using this latest iteration of the Etsy for Android app as much as I did working on it. You can read more over on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.etsy.com/blog/news/2013/more-to-discover-on-etsy-for-ipad-and-android/&#34;&gt;Etsy News blog&lt;/a&gt; announcing the release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven&amp;rsquo;t tried Etsy for Android on your tablet or phone just head to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.etsy.android&#34;&gt;Google Play store&lt;/a&gt; to download the app.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vodafone Usage Unpublished</title>
      <link>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/vodafone-usage-unpublished/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 00:48:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/vodafone-usage-unpublished/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have decided after much consideration to discontinue any further development and support of both the free and paid versions of the Vodafone Usage Android app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recent change by Vodafone to their website has meant that the app is no longer functioning. As I&amp;rsquo;m no longer living in Australia or a Vodafone customer myself it&amp;rsquo;s become near impossible to provide support or further updates to the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, since I originally built the app over 3 years ago, Vodafone have themselves come to the Android party and develop their own usage meter app. For all those seeking alternatives I regretfully encourage you to download their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vodafone.com.au/personal/apps/home/my-vodafone-app&#34;&gt;My Vodafone app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my first ever Android app. It has been a fun journey. I want to thank the over 70,000 users who have downloaded and used the app. To all those who purchased the paid upgrade thank you as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve made a recent purchase of Vodafone Usage Plus I&amp;rsquo;ll be happy to refund your purchase. So please &lt;a href=&#34;http://themodernink.com/contact/&#34;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dash 1.3 is out</title>
      <link>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/dash-1-3-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2013 04:40:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/dash-1-3-is-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yep it&amp;rsquo;s here! This long awaited release of Dash for App.net brings support for private messages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now chat privately with all your App.net followers, anytime, anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Better yet existing Dash Plus features such as push notifications for mentions and background updates of streams are now totally free for all. That&amp;rsquo;s pretty big news for all you Android App.net fans out there. I&amp;rsquo;ll be expanding push notifications in the coming weeks to support private messages and more. So stayed tuned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dash v1.3 is rolling out now. &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/getdash&#34;&gt;Go on. Try it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[gallery type=&amp;ldquo;slideshow&amp;rdquo; link=&amp;ldquo;file&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;343,344,346,347,345,348&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving Solved Problems</title>
      <link>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/action-bar-compat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 03:35:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/action-bar-compat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week Google simultaneously announced and released &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/about/versions/android-4.3.html&#34;&gt;Android 4.3&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The release included a number of new features to the platform plus performance improvements. For developers it brings a number of new API&amp;rsquo;s. They also updated system images, build tools and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/tools/support-library/index.html&#34;&gt;Android support library&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The support library exists to bring backwards-compatible support to API&amp;rsquo;s introduced in new Android versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most notably this latest support library update included a new &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/reference/android/support/v7/app/ActionBar.html&#34;&gt;ActionBar&lt;/a&gt; class which allows developers to bring backwards compatible support for the ActionBar, introduced in Android 3.0 (Feb 24th 2011), to Android 2.1+.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here in lies the problem. An extremely popular, globally used and well supported library already exists to solve this problem - see &lt;a href=&#34;http://actionbarsherlock.com/&#34;&gt;ActionBarSherlock&lt;/a&gt;. I use it for Dash, at Etsy, and in most of the other apps I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on. I know other large tech startups use it (Square, GitHub, Foursquare) and even Google themselves included ActionBarSherlock in their 2012 Google I/O app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we&amp;rsquo;re halfway through 2013, instead of solving a solved problem, Google could have taken the opportunity to include support for new Android 4.3 API&amp;rsquo;s in the support library. Like the awesome new &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/about/versions/android-4.3.html#UI&#34;&gt;ViewOverlay&lt;/a&gt; or Optical Bounds Layouts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This would help solve an unsolved problem, the bittersweet situation after each Android platform release where we developers realise it&amp;rsquo;ll be a long time before we can use any of the new features annouced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe the best Google can do when it comes to compatibility is a 2 year timeframe? Guess we&amp;rsquo;ll have to wait and see.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dash 1.0 for App.net</title>
      <link>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/dash-1-0-for-app-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 06:05:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/dash-1-0-for-app-net/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://denizmveli.github.io/img/wp-uploads/2012/11/featuregraphic_square1.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://denizmveli.github.io/img/wp-uploads/2012/11/featuregraphic_square1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last few weeks, while working on bringing the latest and greatest features to Hooha, I&amp;rsquo;ve kept a constant focus on user feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest piece of feedback received was &amp;ldquo;Love the app, hate the name&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt this update released today, which brings the app out of beta, was an appropriate time to spend some effort on the brand. Working together with my good friend &lt;a href=&#34;http://simmple.com.au/&#34;&gt;Toby Simm (Simmple) &lt;/a&gt;on branding and graphic design, I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to bring the new and improved Dash for App.net.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dash is all about speed. It&amp;rsquo;s quick and simple to get in and share with your friends. Share a photo, your location or just a short message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dash is about effortlessly staying up to date. That&amp;rsquo;s why Dash Plus brings you push notifications for your mentions and background updates. You can upgrade to Dash Plus for just 1.99 via in-app purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dash is quickly finding what you want, by searching for a user or a hashtag. And never losing your favourites, just star a post or a hashtag to have it saved on your device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s so much new to Dash 1.0. I really hope you love the app, and love the name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://alpha.app.net/dashapp&#34;&gt;@dashapp&lt;/a&gt; on ADN today to stay up to date with all the latest app news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full release notes are below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[gallery link=&amp;ldquo;file&amp;rdquo; columns=&amp;ldquo;2&amp;rdquo; type=&amp;ldquo;slideshow&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;194,195,196,197,198,199,202&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;v1.0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;★ New name - Dash is your new best mate.
★ New &amp;amp; improved UI!
★ View &amp;amp; share photo&amp;rsquo;s and locations.
★ Search for users &amp;amp; hastags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upgrade to &amp;ldquo;Dash Plus&amp;rdquo; via in app purchase (1.99) to get:
★ Push notifications for mentions.
★ Background updates for your stream, mentions &amp;amp; global.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want more?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;★ View stars and reposts for a particular post.
★ Stream, mentions &amp;amp; global now save scroll position.
★ Load missing posts &amp;amp; refresh threads.
★ Repost has the option to &amp;ldquo;Repost&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Quote&amp;rdquo;.
★ Option to view a unified stream.
★ Improved image loading and scrolling speeds.
★ Redesigned login and authentication flow.
★ Share photo&amp;rsquo;s to Dash from other apps.
★ Lots, lots more&amp;hellip;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.themodernink.hooha&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.android.com/images/brand/get_it_on_play_logo_large.png&#34; alt=&#34;Get it on Google Play&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hooha Update</title>
      <link>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/hooha-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 11:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/hooha-update/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a big couple of weeks for Hooha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week Hooha for App.net was released to Google Play, making it the first native mobile app for App.net on any app store. Say that a few times quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unexpectedly this resulted in a little bit of media coverage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was interviewed for &lt;a href=&#34;http://thenextweb.com/apps/2012/08/27/hooha-first-app-net-android-client-arrives-google-play/&#34;&gt;The Next Web&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soon after this was picked up by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.engadget.com/2012/08/27/app-net-hooha/&#34;&gt;Engadget&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theverge.com/2012/8/27/3272053/app-net-first-android-app-hooha&#34;&gt;The Verge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Guardian mentioned Hooha in it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/appsblog/2012/aug/31/best-android-apps-paralympics-skydrive?CMP=twt_fd&#34;&gt;20 Best Android apps of the week&lt;/a&gt; and then again covering the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.guardian.co.uk/technology/appsblog/2012/sep/03/app-net-iphone-android-apps&#34;&gt;Hooha release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then Mashable said Hooha was one of &lt;a href=&#34;http://mashable.com/2012/09/01/6-apps-you-dont-want-to-miss-2&#34;&gt;6 Apps You Don&amp;rsquo;t Want To Miss&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But all this hooha hasn&amp;rsquo;t stopped the development of more awesome features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hooha v0.7.0 is rolling out to Google Play now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[gallery link=&amp;ldquo;file&amp;rdquo; columns=&amp;ldquo;2&amp;rdquo; type=&amp;ldquo;slideshow&amp;rdquo; ids=&amp;ldquo;164,165,166,167&amp;rdquo;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s in store:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;New side navigation!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Me section to find all your info quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;User views now show posts, followers and following users.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hashtag support!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Share your posts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reply now defaults to reply to all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reposts are replies too so that they appear in the same thread.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Setting to include directed mentions in your stream.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Improved post loading speeds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed thread loading issue with large threads.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that in one massive release. What can you do but go &lt;a href=&#34;http://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.themodernink.hooha&#34;&gt;download it. Now!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.android.com/images/brand/get_it_on_play_logo_large.png&#34; alt=&#34;Get it on Google Play&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hooha for App.net released on Google Play</title>
      <link>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/hooha-for-app-net-released-on-google-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2012 08:13:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/hooha-for-app-net-released-on-google-play/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hooha (formally Jive), a new App.net client built for the community from the ground up is now available for &lt;a href=&#34;http://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.themodernink.hooha&#34;&gt;download from Google Play&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hooha is a beautiful yet simple, minimalistic app designed for readability, while making posting and sharing on App.net from your Android device a piece of cake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://denizmveli.github.io/img/wp-uploads/2012/08/Screen6main.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://denizmveli.github.io/img/wp-uploads/2012/08/Screen6main-670x1191.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s App.net? It&amp;rsquo;s a different kind of social platform. A real-time social service where users and developers come first, not advertisers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t have an App.net account? Want to be an appster, or an appdotnetter? &lt;a href=&#34;https://join.app.net&#34;&gt;https://join.app.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got App.net? Then go get Hooha and see what all the hooha is about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.themodernink.hooha&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.android.com/images/brand/get_it_on_play_logo_large.png&#34; alt=&#34;Get it on Google Play&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Say hello to Jive</title>
      <link>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/say-hello-to-jive/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2012 03:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/say-hello-to-jive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;UPDATE: Jive is no more. Our renamed app &lt;a href=&#34;http://themodernink.com/hooha-for-app-net-released-on-google-play/&#34;&gt;Hooha is now available on Google Play&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say hello to Jive, a brand new Android app for the brand new platform App.net.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://denizmveli.github.io/img/wp-uploads/2012/08/Screen1-v01.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://denizmveli.github.io/img/wp-uploads/2012/08/Screen1-v01-670x1191.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a very raw alpha build so please be aware the app is in no way complete. Then again neither is App.net so lets just roll with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things Jive can do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;View your stream, mentions and global posts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Compose a new post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reply or repost other posts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open links from posts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Android 2.2 +&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things Jive will have soon:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;User handling - @user tags will open in your mobile browser at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hashtag handling - #hashtags will open in your mobile browser at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Better refresh - refresh blows away the stream and loads it again. It needs to be smarter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Background loading.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;More and more awesome features.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have access to App.net alpha please try out Jive and let me know what you think. If not &lt;a href=&#34;http://join.app.net&#34;&gt;http://join.app.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s an option in-app to send feedback. I&amp;rsquo;d really appreciate it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE : v 0.2.0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Share links/text from other Android apps to Jive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tab select scroll to top.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Drop down options to reply and repost from stream.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fixed sort order of posts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Display usernames instead of full names.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;Download Jive for App.net Version 0.2&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE !!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve taken the download link down as there&amp;rsquo;s legal issues with using the name Jive. A new version of the app will be available in the next few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://themodernink.com/hooha-for-app-net-released-on-google-play/&#34;&gt;You can get Hooha for App.net now from Google Play.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly you can follow me &lt;a href=&#34;http://alpha.app.net/deniz&#34;&gt;@deniz on App.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Parx comes to Android</title>
      <link>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/my-parx-comes-to-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2012 12:57:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/my-parx-comes-to-android/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://denizmveli.github.io/img/wp-uploads/2012/06/MyParx1.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://denizmveli.github.io/img/wp-uploads/2012/06/MyParx1-670x1170.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Modern Ink&amp;rsquo;s been working with the team at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.two-bulls.com&#34;&gt;Two Bulls&lt;/a&gt; to bring their unique parks platform app to Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app aims to stay true to the My Parx branding, provide all of the features of it&amp;rsquo;s iOS counter part whilst still maintaining a natively Android user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what&amp;rsquo;s My Parx all about? My Parx helps you find and explore parks that interest you. Discover the secrets of your favourite parks through exploring up-to-date information, interactive maps, and personal guided tours - produced by those who know the parks best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Parx is location-aware, so you can discover nearby parks or take interactive guided tours as you explore parks right on your phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And best of all, it&amp;rsquo;s free. Try it now on Google Play&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.myparx.android&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.android.com/images/brand/get_it_on_play_logo_large.png&#34; alt=&#34;Available in Android Market&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find out more or get your local park involved, head on over to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myparx.com&#34;&gt;My Parx website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>App Design of Instagram for Android</title>
      <link>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/app-design-of-instagram-for-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2012 07:50:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://denizmveli.github.io/_posts/app-design-of-instagram-for-android/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instagram&lt;/strong&gt;. Over 27 million users and Apples App Store App of the Year for 2011.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, after much anticipation by many Android users, Instagram for Android was released and has already clocked over one million downloads. That&amp;rsquo;s not surprising given the popularity of the photo sharing social network, previously exclusive to the iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With so much anticipation and buzz surrounding the release, including myself signing up for email notifications pre-release, I was naturally excited to hit Google Play and see what the developers and designers at Instagram had put together. In fact I  downloaded it in bed before I had my breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s not crazy&amp;hellip; I wanted to know a few things. Was the app going to deliver a uniquely Android experience? Maybe it&amp;rsquo;d be a straight&amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo;lazy port of the iPhone app? Or maybe the developers would choose a safe middle ground between the two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: I won&amp;rsquo;t be commenting on features the app has or doesn&amp;rsquo;t have on each platform. This is purely a discussion about Android app design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First impressions&lt;/strong&gt;. After getting through the login screen I&amp;rsquo;m presented with the Instagram home screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://denizmveli.github.io/img/wp-uploads/2012/04/instagram1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://denizmveli.github.io/img/wp-uploads/2012/04/instagram1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Instagram for Android home screen&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the top of the screen Instagram have implemented the &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/design/patterns/actionbar.html&#34;&gt;Android action bar&lt;/a&gt;. Google have been pushing the action bar pattern to developers a lot in recent times. Through the design of their own Android apps, in the new &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/design/index.html&#34;&gt;Android design guidelines&lt;/a&gt;, and even at Google&amp;rsquo;s developer labs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of app navigation this is now the standard for where you should start on Android. Instagram&amp;rsquo;s implementation is however a faux action bar that runs a little differently to the native control available on phones running Android 4.0+ (I tried it out on a Nexus S). A key feature of the Android 4.0 action bar is that it supports integration with tabs for navigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the bottom of the main screen there is the tab bar for navigation between the four main sections of the app, with a fifth centred tab button which takes you to the camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This all looks great graphically. The various buttons and text elements on both the action bar and the tab control are styled beautifully. However, in terms of function both elements behave unexpectedly at times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most interested parties would probably note that the tabs are on the bottom and that Google states &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/design/patterns/pure-android.html&#34;&gt;Android tabs should be at the top,&lt;/a&gt; beneath the action bar. It&amp;rsquo;s a common fault it seems when apps are ported from iPhone to Android. However this is not my main issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My issue is with the behaviour of the tabs when the back button is pressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://denizmveli.github.io/img/wp-uploads/2012/04/instagram_tabs1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instagram&amp;rsquo;s developers have decided to layer each tab change on the back stack of the app so that pressing the back button navigates back through the tabs you&amp;rsquo;ve previously selected. It instantly feels unfamiliar and you&amp;rsquo;re not sure when the app will let you exit it completely. This fake back trail continues until you hit the home tab where you entered the app and then the back button let&amp;rsquo;s you exit the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is completely unnatural for an Android user. The expected behaviour of the back button is to exit the activity that the user is viewing. If the activity was the main activity that the user launched then the back button will exit the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a development point of the view a lot of effort would have gone into making the tabs function this way. But it was a mistake. It&amp;rsquo;s not expected behaviour on Android and it&amp;rsquo;s surprising that Instagram have ended up with this implementation. At the end of the day this is the core of the apps navigation that should function as expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another issue I have with the tabs is that they are permanent. What this means is that opening up sub-views, say from within the list of photo&amp;rsquo;s on the home tab doesn&amp;rsquo;t open a new activity, it opens up a sub-view within the main view leaving the tab bar in place. What&amp;rsquo;s the result?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://denizmveli.github.io/img/wp-uploads/2012/04/instagram2.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://denizmveli.github.io/img/wp-uploads/2012/04/instagram2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because there are no new activities, and only new views within the tab activity there are **no animations **between views. This makes for a very short, sharp and jolty experience when you are switching between the various tabs &amp;amp; views throughout the app. People complain that Android lacks the animation polish of iOS, but it&amp;rsquo;s mostly bad implementations that give this impression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My last issue with the tabs is that they could have easily implemented &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/design/patterns/swipe-views.html&#34;&gt;view swiping&lt;/a&gt; between the main tab views. This would have made the app feel more like a native Android app and less like an iPhone port.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have other issues with the action bar, fixed list view headers.. I could go on&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the overall verdict. For all the buzz, Instagram have delivered a nice looking, well-functioning Android app. But it&amp;rsquo;s definitely not a masterclass in Android app design. Or even a beginners class. If you yourself are porting an iOS app and looking at Instagram on Android as an example of how it&amp;rsquo;s done. You are on the wrong track. &lt;a href=&#34;http://developer.android.com/design&#34;&gt;Start here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll post some better examples of ports, to give a comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>