<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Android on Deniz Veli | The Modern Ink</title>
    <link>https://themodernink.com/tags/android/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Android on Deniz Veli | The Modern Ink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Deniz Veli 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 05:15:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://themodernink.com/tags/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Etsy Local Goes Mobile</title>
      <link>https://themodernink.com/etsy-local-goes-mobile/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 05:15:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://themodernink.com/etsy-local-goes-mobile/</guid>
      <description>Last week my anxiety and anticipation was building, as a whole lot of work from a great team of individuals I lead at Etsy was just about to be released to the world. And that feeling is exactly what I get out of bed and go to work for.
And then we launched the all new Etsy Local home screen tab on the Etsy app the iOS and Android!
With Etsy Local you can find Etsy items and sellers near you, at events like pop-ups, craft fairs, and flea markets or local shops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beautiful Android Design</title>
      <link>https://themodernink.com/beautiful-android-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 07:04:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://themodernink.com/beautiful-android-design/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m super excited and very honored that Google recently placed our latest Etsy Android app on a very short list of the best Android apps released this season.
You can read more over on the Android Developers blog and if you haven&amp;rsquo;t yet been shopping on the new Etsy for Android app on your tablet or phone, this might be just the reminder you need.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Etsy Android Staggered Grid</title>
      <link>https://themodernink.com/etsy-android-staggered-grid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2013 22:13:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://themodernink.com/etsy-android-staggered-grid/</guid>
      <description>Last week at Etsy we open sourced the staggered grid view from the new Etsy Android app. Somewhat surprisingly there&amp;rsquo;s been a large amount of interest from the Android community. I guess I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised. Whilst working on various apps I&amp;rsquo;ve found it challenging to implement advanced UI elements such as the staggered or masonry grid.
Thankfully I had the opportunity during a recent project at Etsy to implement this grid view that would support advanced features such as rows of varying heights &amp;amp; syncing row positions across orientation changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dash 1.3 is out</title>
      <link>https://themodernink.com/dash-1-3-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2013 04:40:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://themodernink.com/dash-1-3-is-out/</guid>
      <description>Yep it&amp;rsquo;s here! This long awaited release of Dash for App.net brings support for private messages.
You can now chat privately with all your App.net followers, anytime, anywhere.
Better yet existing Dash Plus features such as push notifications for mentions and background updates of streams are now totally free for all. That&amp;rsquo;s pretty big news for all you Android App.net fans out there. I&amp;rsquo;ll be expanding push notifications in the coming weeks to support private messages and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving Solved Problems</title>
      <link>https://themodernink.com/action-bar-compat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 03:35:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://themodernink.com/action-bar-compat/</guid>
      <description>Last week Google simultaneously announced and released Android 4.3.
The release included a number of new features to the platform plus performance improvements. For developers it brings a number of new API&amp;rsquo;s. They also updated system images, build tools and the Android support library.
The support library exists to bring backwards-compatible support to API&amp;rsquo;s introduced in new Android versions.
Most notably this latest support library update included a new ActionBar class which allows developers to bring backwards compatible support for the ActionBar, introduced in Android 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dash 1.0 for App.net</title>
      <link>https://themodernink.com/dash-1-0-for-app-net/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 06:05:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://themodernink.com/dash-1-0-for-app-net/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few weeks, while working on bringing the latest and greatest features to Hooha, I&amp;rsquo;ve kept a constant focus on user feedback.
The biggest piece of feedback received was &amp;ldquo;Love the app, hate the name&amp;rdquo;.
I felt this update released today, which brings the app out of beta, was an appropriate time to spend some effort on the brand. Working together with my good friend Toby Simm (Simmple) on branding and graphic design, I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to bring the new and improved Dash for App.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>